Mohammad Rafi Amin

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer passionate about crafting applications in Ruby, React, and JavaScript, boasting over 2 years of experience in developing solutions for projects of diverse scales. An ardent advocate of pair programming and emerging technologies, showcasing a knack for rapid and proficient adaptability and learning.

EXPERIENCE

Self-employed, Remote

Full-stack Developer, April 2022 - Present

- Built over 40 projects using different tech-stacks: HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, React/Redux, Ruby on Rails. Some of the projects are included.
- **StockList App**: A frontend web application that displays a catalog of financial values using Stock API. The app showcases a list of active stocks as well as daily gainers and losers. Built the whole application from the ground up. <u>Visit-site</u>:
- JustCold Web App: A full-stack app built using React as Frontend & Ruby on Rails as the Backend. The E-commerce app allows clients to see a list of Products and buy it. Visit-site:

CodeClause, India · Remote

Web Development Intern, Sep 2023 - Present

- At CodeClause, I embarked on a web development internship where I had the chance to delve into cutting-edge technologies, including React, Redux, and postgresql, while actively contributing to the development of responsive and scalable web applications.
- During my internship at CodeClause, I collaborated closely with experienced developers, participated in agile development processes, and gained valuable insights into best practices for building robust web solutions, solidifying my skills and knowledge in the field <u>Visit-Site</u>:

TECH-A-INTERN, India · Remote

Web Development and Designing Internship, Sep 2023 - Present

- As a web development intern at Tech A, I actively contributed to the development and maintenance of web applications, gaining hands-on experience in front-end and back-end technologies, while collaborating with a dynamic team to deliver high-quality solutions.
- During my internship at Tech A, I had the opportunity to work on real-world projects, improving my skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and honing my problem-solving abilities by tackling complex coding challenges in a fast-paced and innovative environment. Visit-Site:

TechnoHacks, India · Remote

Web Development Internship, August 2023 - Present

- Collaborated with a dynamic team to craft and implement web solutions, contributing to the successful launch of 5+ projects, resulting in a 20% increase in client satisfaction.
- Developed front-end interfaces for 5+ websites, optimizing user experience and reducing page load times by an average of 2 seconds. <u>Visit-Site</u>:

mrkamin2@gmail.com
Portfolio | Github |
LinkedIn | AngelList |
Medium | Twitter

SKILLS

Front-End:

JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Sass, Capybara, RSpec

Back-End:

Nodejs, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSql,

Tools & Methods:

Git, GitHub, Gitlab, Mobile/Responsive Development

Professional:

Remote,
Pair-Programming,
Teamwork, Mentoring,
Collaboration

PROJECTS

Doctor Appointment

This project is to make an appointment with a doctor. Doctor Reservation frontend is React frontend application for doctor book appointments. This application is responsive, and users can load, create, and delete doctors and reservations. Users need to sign up or sign in to access the application. They can sign up or sign in using the sign up and login forms.

Built with: JavaScript |
 React | Ruby on Rails |
 Postgresql | HTML | CSS

GAO RFID Inc, New York, United States • Remote

Software Developer Internship, April 2023 - August 2023

- Spearheaded the creation and enhancement of content for company sub-industry websites, leading to a 30% boost in monthly page views and engagement.
- Utilized React and critical libraries to optimize front-end performance, resulting in a 40% decrease in website bounce rate <u>VisitSites</u>:

Moby Media Group, Kabul (Afghanistan)

Network Administrator, July 2017 - March 2022

- Pioneered the setup and maintenance of network resources from the ground up, ensuring seamless connectivity for 500+ number of employees and departments.
- Implemented security protocols that reduced network vulnerabilities by 99.9%, safeguarding sensitive company data. <u>VisitSites</u>:

Sunlight Electricity Services Company, Kabul (Afghanistan) IT Support Engineer, July 2012 – July 2017

- Modernized IT equipment and streamlined support processes, leading to a 80% increase in user satisfaction as measured by post-support surveys.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to troubleshoot and resolve an average of 8+ technical issues daily, contributing to a 99.9% decrease in overall operational downtime.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE, Sep 2022 - Present

Full-stack web Development, Computer Software Engineering

- Activities and societies: Student Mentor, 8 Hrs daily coding, Remote-pair-programming, Code-review.
- Spent 2000+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard Gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

Kabul University, September 2009 – July 2013 Bachelor Computer Science

VOLUNTEERING

MICROVERSE, Sep 2022 - Present, Student Mentor

- Mentoring junior web developers, and providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposing improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.

. View on Github

Food Recipe

The JavaScript capstone project is about building a web application based on an external API. The web app will have 2 or 3 user interfaces. the user can see the list of foods and is able to put comments and likes to each food.

- **Built with:** JavaScript | Webpack | HTML | CSS

. View on Github

Space Travelers Hub

This is a React WebApp with real live data from the SpaceX API. The application will allow users to book rockets and join selected space missions.

- Built with: JavaScript | React | HTML | CSS . View on Github

To-Do list

A todo list is a practical tool for organizing tasks. It allows users to input, prioritize, and track activities, enhancing productivity and goal management in various aspects of life.

- **Built with:** JavaScript | Webpack | HTML | CSS
- . View on Github